Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/chuckmckinney (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

T-SQL Stored Procedures
Query Writing
Analytics

Languages

English

Certifications

Introducing .NET Core
Learning SQL Programming
Introduction to Blazor
Visual Studio for Unity Developers
SQL Programming

Publications

Inscape

Chuck McKinney

A machine that turns coffee into code! Harrodsburg, Kentucky, United States

Summary

Applications Developer. My primary work life has been in SQL, creating and maintaining databases and objects for storage and application use. This has included C# for web and desktop applications, Power BI and Power Apps, and custom in house programs that interact with various data connections. I have skills in using the classic CRUD statements to create reports as well as issue tracking through dependencies, custom functions, stored procedures, automatic email reporting, scheduled job activities, and snapshot/transactional replication.

I also have experience in creating RestAPIs, Web Clients, desktop applications (such as a host monitor app), HTML development, and jumping into older applications to update them to new/modern code languages. I am experienced working in test environments and pushing features through versions.

I take each challenge that I come across as a learning experience and am always ready to try something new!

Experience

Corning Incorporated Application Developer/Support Analyst November 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Harrodsburg, Kentucky, United States

.Net 6 Web - Created new .Net 6 RestAPI for various data collection and reporting. Created a security token system for local data access. Created a .Net 6 Universal Web Client for housing web pages from multiple internal websites as well as connecting to the RestAPI. Built multiple Blazor Web Applications for production and operation needs. Applications included reporting systems, user management systems, and data visualization applications. Took pre-existing VB6 and .Net Framework applications and recreated them as .Net 6 Web Applications.

Git - Managed plant Git repositories; managing branches, protecting versions, developer/user access. This includes code reviews and approvals for internal and external developers.

SQL - Worked on SQL Server Database install sets for various projects. Generated SQL report scripts for various reports or scheduled jobs.

Creative Liquid Coatings
IT Systems Engineer
September 2017 - November 2021 (4 years 3 months)
Nicholasville. KY

Programming: Develop modern/user friendly programs and applications for windows, android, and ios using a DB2/AS400 database. This includes reports, dashboards, and input screens for data collections. C#, VB.NET, HTML, SQL, .Net Framework, .Net Core, RestAPI, Xamarin Forms, ASP.Net (Core and MVC). Created Power Bi reports and Dashboards using SQL via data pipelines. Assisted the Quality department in creating and updated work instructions and procedures throughout the plant. Programmed a new Document Control System. Worked with all departments throughout both MVC facilities to develop hands on programs to deliver data and efficiency.

Hardware: Cross managed Active Directory, computer upgrades/imaging, scanner terminal repairs, thermal label printer repairs, and hardware support requests (Monitors, Keyboards, etc.). Organized the IT storeroom to a 5S system for check in/check out of equipment and enforce hardware inspections and tracking. Managed Ticket System/Help Desk to ensure customers get issues and requests resolved in a timely manner.

Additional support: 3D/2D layout and prototype modeling as well as vinyl sign creation and plotter requests.

*Company previously MVCUSA before being purchased in Aug 2021

DecoArt

Technical Support Specialist
July 2015 - September 2017 (2 years 3 months)
Stanford Ky

Developed efficient processes to streamline production. Created in-depth training videos on jobs throughout the facility. Managed a central controlled

document library. Updated and managed company CAD files. Created VBA excel forms for quick data entry. Assigned inventory part locations based on size dimensions and priorities. Monitored the inventory tracking system. I am first call for issues and general assistance when problems occur.

Corning Incorporated
Industrial Technical Writer
May 2012 - July 2015 (3 years 3 months)
Harrodsburg Ky

Project 4: Worked on a private project. Created, reformatted, and monitored quality assurance documentation. Performed quality inspections and monitored data to ensure products were within the quality standards set. Maintained quality standards in an ever changing environment.

Project 3: Developed a new training format which included demonstrations, certifications, and on the job training materials for various jobs. Also helped write new operating procedures as needed. Jobs included Mixing Operator, Warehouse Operator, Display Glass Associate, Bottom of Draw Associate, and Sheet Glass Operator.

Project 2: Wrote procedure documents as well as edited preexisting documents into the new desired formats. Also documented all equipment in specific sectors of this Department

Project 1: Reformatted and reorganized all existing documents. Also created several documents based on existing power points and assisted in many other projects as needed.

Education

Morehead State University
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Fine and Studio Arts · (2008 - 2012)